Postcards
Marist Archives and Special Collections
- Postcards, 2.1.7
  - Africa (birds) [John Hinde postcards], undated; 5 (Box 1599)
    - East African Crowned Crane., 8
    - EAST AFRICAN CROWNED CRANE (Balearica pavonia). Feeds on insects and grain. They breed in marshy areas laying two or three eggs. Photographed, Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland, 8-verso
    - Vulturine Guinea-fowl., 9
    - VULTURINE GUINEA-FOWL (Acryllium vulturinum). The largest and most attractive of the seven species of Guinea-fowl to be found in Africa. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 9-verso
    - African Butterfly., 10
    - A female Precis octavia Cramer, dry season form sesamus Trimen; this butterfly is a member of the Nymphalidae. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland, 10-verso
  - Africa (animals) [John Hinde postcards], undated; 6 (Box 1599)
    - African Crocodile. Photo: E. Ludwig, John Hinde Studios, 1
    - AFRICAN CROCODILE (Crocodylus niloticus). These huge reptiles spend the day basking on river banks, entering the water in the evening to hunt. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland, 1-verso
    - Grant's Zebra., 2
    - GRANT'S ZEBRA (Equus burchelli boehmi). There are several species distinguished by size and markings; while still abundant, some species have become extinct. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland, 2-verso
    - Antelope., 3
    - ANTELOPE: As the hot African sun lowers in the evening, many Antelope may be seen grazing on the Savannah Plains. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland, 3-verso
    - Baby Thomson's Gazelle., 4
    - THOMSON'S GAZELLE (Gazelle Thomsonii). Better known as 'Tommies' and found only in East Africa; this youngster has not yet grown his horns. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 4-verso
    - Cape Buffalo and Egyptian Geese., 5
    - CAPE BUFFALO (Syncerus Caffer). Old bulls are often seen near water and care must be taken in approaching these dangerous animals. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 5-verso
    - Warthog., 6
    - WARTHOG (Phacochoerus aethiopicus). Despite their ferocious appearance, they are seldom aggressive; the tusks are used more for digging roots and tubers. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 6-verso
    - Topi. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 7
    - THE TOPI (Damaliscus korrigum jimela). A variety of antelope found in open parkland country. Distinguished by the angular curved horns. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 7-verso
    - Cheetah. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 8
    - THE CHEETAH (Acinonyx jubatus). The world's fastest animal-unlike the leopard they cannot climb. Young animals can be tamed and trained to hunt. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 8-verso
    - Leopard. Color Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 9
    - THE LEOPARD (Felis pardus). A powerful and agile animal. Having killed an antelope will often carry the carcase into a high tree. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 9-verso
    - Cheetah., 10
    - CHEETAH (Acinonyx Jubatus). The world's fastest animal for short distances, they can reach 60 m.p.h. The Antelope had no chance from this family. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 10-verso
    - Leopard., 11
    - THE LEOPARD (Felis pardus). A powerful and agile animal. Having killed an antelope will often carry the carcase into a high tree. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 11-verso
    - Cheetah. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 12
    - THE CHEETAH (Acinonyx jubatus). Considered the world's fastest animal, the legs have dog-like paws with non-retractile claws. Runs down its prey. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 12-verso
    - African Elephant. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 13
    - THE ELEPHANT (Elephas africanus). A large bull may weigh 3-5 tons and the ivory tusks, which are enlarged incisors, may weigh 200 lbs. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 13-verso
    - African Elephant and Marabous. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 14
    - THE ELEPHANT (Elephas africanus). A large bull may weigh 3-5 tons and the ivory tusks, which are enlarged incisors, may weigh 200 lbs. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 14-verso
    - African Elephant. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 15
    - THE ELEPHANT (Elephas africanus). The most impressive of African animals. A large bull weighs 3-5 tons. The life span is about 50 years. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 15-verso
    - African Elephant and calf. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 16
    - AFRICAN ELEPHANT (Elephas africanus). Young are born after a gestation period of 22 months and suckled for 3 years. Mature at 14 years. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 16-verso
    - Elephant Herd., 17
    - THE ELEPHANT. (Loxodonata africanus). The most impressive of African animals. A large bull weighs 3-5 tons. The life span is about 50 years. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 17-verso
    - African Elephant and calf., 18
    - AFRICAN ELEPHANT. (Loxodonata africanus). Young are born after a gestation period of 22 months and suckled for 3 years. Mature at 14 years. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 18-verso
    - Lioness with cubs., 19
    - LIONESS (Panthera Leo) in the shade with her family of 3 month old cubs, who will remain with her until fully grown. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 19-verso
    - Lions and Lioness. Colour Pholo by john Hinde, F.R.P.S., 20
    - THE LION (Felis leo). Large males are 3' 6" high with an overall length of nearly 10' and weighing 450 lbs. Females are smaller. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 20-verso
    - Lioness. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 21
    - LIONESS (Panthera Leo) relaxing in the heat of the sun. These animals usually hunt early morning or in the evening Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 21-verso
    - Lion Cub., 22
    - LION CUB: A month old lion cub waiting patiently in the shade for its mother to return from a hunting trip. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 22-verso
    - Lioness, 23
    - LIONESS (Panthera Leo) satisfies her thirst from a water hole during the heat of the day. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 23-verso
    - Lioness and cub., 24
    - LIONESS (Panthera Leo). A 3 month old cub nestles near its mother who rests in the heat of the African sun. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 24-verso
    - Lion and Lioness. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 25
    - THE LION (Felis leo). Large males are 3' 6" high with an overall length of nearly 10' and weighing 450 lbs. Females are smaller. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 25-verso
    - Lion, Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 26
    - THE AFRICAN LION (Felis leo). Naturally lazy animals, they hunt only when necessary and then lie in the shade most of the day. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 26-verso
    - Lioness and Antelope. Colour Photo by John Hindt, F.R.P.S., 27
    - An unusual photograph taken in Africa of a lioness (Felis leo) with a very young antelope. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 27-verso
    - Grant's Zebra and Giraffe. Colour Photo by John Hinde, F.R.P.S., 28
    - THE GIRAFFE (Giraffa camelopardalis). GRANT'S ZEBRA (Equus burchelli boehmi). The giraffe has the same number of bones in the neck as the zebra. Photographed, Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 28-verso
    - Hippopotamus., 29
    - HIPPOPOTAMUS (Hippopotamus amphibius). These animals spend most of the day in water and come out in the evening to graze. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 29-verso
    - Hippopotamus and Egyptian Geese., 30
    - HIPPOPOTAMUS (Hippopotamus amphibius) and EGYPTIAN GEESE (Alopochen aegyptiacus). The former is found on almost every river or lake in Africa. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 30-verso
    - Wildebeest., 31
    - WILDEBEEST (Connochaetes taurinus). Vast herds of these animals may be found in many parts of Africa, often mingling with Zebra. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 31-verso
    - Caracal., 32
    - CARACAL (Lynx caracal). An unusual photograph of a mother feeding her cubs. These cats, although small, are powerful animals and can even hunt down gazelle. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 32-verso
    - Giraffe., 33
    - THE GIRAFFE (Giraffa camelopardalis). Height up to 19'. Weight over 1 ton. Feeds on Acacia trees, stripping the leaves with its tongue. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 33-verso
    - Grant's Zebra., 34
    - GRANT'S ZEBRA (Equus burchelli boehmi). There are several species distinguished by size and markings; while still abundant, some species have become extinct. Printed, and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland, 34-verso
    - Lion reclining up a tree., 35
    - THE AFRICAN LION (Felis leo). Naturally lazy animals, they hunt only when necessary and then lie in the shade most of the day. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 35-verso
    - African Ground Squirrel., 36
    - AFRICAN GROUND SQUIRREL (Xerus rutilus). These little rodents spend most of their time in the dry country hunting for birds eggs, roots and grain. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 36-verso
    - Spotted Hyena., 37
    - SPOTTED HYENA (Crocuta crocuta). Not usually hunters, they prefer to scavenge; but, having just savaged a wildebeest they begin to disembowel their prey. Printed and Published by John Hinde Limited, Cabinteely Co. Dublin, Republic of Ireland., 37-verso
  - Austria, circa 1922; 7 (Box 1599)
    - [View of a town, river and mountains], 1
    - Bad Ischl, Salzkammergut, June 18th, 1922., 1-verso
    - [Cityscape from view of river shoreline, with a steamboat, people in a boat and a horse pulling a cart] [View of the Austrian city of Linz from the Danube River], 2
    - Alpenlandische Kunst [Alpine Art]; Linz a.d. Donau [Danube River], 2-verso
    - [Landscape view of a train] [Electric railway going through the Austrian city of Linz], 3
    - LINZ a./D., Postlingbergbahn [Mountain tramway]. Kunstverlag Hans Hausner, Wien, VA., 3-verso
  - Vienna, Austria, circa 1922; 8 (Box 1599)
    - [Streetview of automobiles and people walking in Stefansplatz, Vienna], 1
    - Wiener Kunst [Vienna Art]. Wien. [Vienna]--Stefansplatz. Erwin Pendl pinx., 1-verso
    - Wien. Rathus. [Vienna. City Hall], 2
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 2-verso
    - Wein I. Rathaus mit Rathauspark [Vienna City Hall and Park], 3
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 3-verso
    - Wien. Burgthor. [Vienna], 4
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 4-verso
    - Wien Stephansplatz, Erwin Pendl gem. [Church building, street and 2 white horses drawing a carriage], 5
    - Wiener Kunstler Postkarte. [Viennese Artist Postcard], 5-verso
    - [Woman with two children and a dog in front of the Minorities Church in Vienna], 6
    - Wein, Minoritenkirche. [Vienna, Minorities Church], 6-verso
    - Wien, Schonbrunn [Schonbrunn Palace in Vienna], 7
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 7-verso
    - Wien, Stefansdom [St. Stephen's Cathedral, Vienna], 8
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 8-verso
    - Wien, I. Freiheitsplatz mit Votivkirche [Liberty Square with Votive Church, Vienna], 9
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 9-verso
    - [View of Graben street, Vienna], 10
    - Wien- Graben [Graban, Vienna], 10-verso
    - [Viennese Art rendition of a University in Vienna], 11
    - Wiener Kunst, Wien.- Universitat. [Vienna, University], 11-verso
    - Wien. Museum. [view of a museum in Vienna], 12
    - Wiener Kunst, 12-verso
    - Wien, I. Operntheater [opera theater in Vienna], 13
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 13-verso
    - Wien, I. Ring des 12. November. [View of many buildings from a high point] [View of the Austrian Parliament within the Ring, Vienna], 14
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 14-verso
    - Wien, Universitat mit Liebenbergdenkmal [University of Vienna and the Liebenberg Monument], 15
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 15-verso
    - Wien, II. Praterstern mit Tegetthoff-Denkmal [Praterstern streetview with Tegetthoff Memorial], 16
    - Kunstler Postkarte, 16-verso
    - Wien, Althanplatz [View of a street with cable cars], 17
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 17-verso
    - [ Linz Main Square with a view of the Trinity Column monument], 18
    - Verso: [LINZ], 18-verso
    - [View of the Trinity Monument and Church of Saints Michael and Ursula, Linz], 19
    - Verso: [LINZ a./S/, Franz Josefs-Platz (Emperor Franz Joseph's Place)], 19-verso
  - Brussels, Belgium, undated; 9 (Box 1599)
    - Bruxelles, Manneken-Pis [close up view of a fountain statue of a little boy peeing], 1
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 1-verso
    - Bruxelles, Manneken-Pis [Fountain statue of a little boy peeing], 2
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 2-verso
    - Bruxelles, Monument Manneken-Pis [Fountain Statue of a little boy peeing], 3
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 3-verso
    - Waterloo, The three Monuments, 4
    - THE THREE MONUMENTS- To the left the Monument to the Hanovrians (it consists of a truncated blue stone pyramid) erected in 1818; in the midst, the lion mountain and on the right, a coloumn dedicated to the memory of Sir Alexander Gordon, aide-de-camp (Knight at Arms) of the duke of Wellington, deadly wounded at the end of the battle., 4-verso
    - Bruxelles. Hotel de Ville. C'est en 1401 que fut commencee l'aile gauche, J. Van Theinnen fournit les plans ainsi que ceux de la partie infeiere de la tour. Van Ruysbroeck fut charge de l'achever er de faire les plans, elle est surmontee par la statue de saint Michel, patron de la Ville, la tour a 114 metres de hauteur. [Brussels Town Hall][1401 was the start of the left wing. J. Van Theinnen provided the plans as well as the lower part of the tower. Van Ruysbroeck was responsible for completing the plans first. It is surmounted by a statue of St. Michael, the patron of the City; the tower 114 meters high], 5
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 5-verso
    - Bruxelles, Eglise Sainte-Gudule [Cathedral of St. Michael and St. Gudula in Brussels]], 6
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 6-verso
    - Bruxelles- Place de Brouchere et Boulevard Anspach [Boulevard Anspach, a major street in the city of Brussels], 7
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 7-verso
    - Waterloo, The three Monuments, 8
    - THE THREE MONUMENTS- To the left the Monument to the Hanovrians (it consists of a truncated blue stone pyramid) erected in 1818; in the midst, the lion mountain and on the right, a coloumn dedicated to the memory of Sir Alexander Gordon, aide-de-camp (Knight at Arms) of the duke of Wellington, deadly wounded at the end of the battle., 8-verso
    - Bruxelles, Place Rogier et Boulevard Botanique [View two major roads in Brussels, Rogier Place and Bontanique Boulevard, from above], 9
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 9-verso
    - Bruxelles- Palais de Justice. Oevre de l'architecture Paelaert. Un des plus grands monuments du monde. Sa superficie est de 24,000 metres carres, s'eleve sur un soubassement rectangulaire de 180 metres de long et 170 de large, le Dome est fe 122 metres au-dessus du pave de la Rue, la Salre de Pas-Perdus a une hauteur de 97 metres; il possede 27 grandes salles, 245 pieces diverses et 8 cours, Inaugure en 1883. Sa construction dura 17 ans. (F. W. reproduction interdite.) [View of law courts of Brussels] [Work of architecture by [Phillip]Poelaert. One of the greatest monuments in the world. Its area is 24,000 square meters, rises on a rectangular base 180 meters long and 170 wide, the Dome is 122 meters above the street, the concourse has a height of 97 meters. It has 27 large rooms, 245 rooms and 8 different courses. Inaugurated in 1883. Its construction lasted 17 years. (F. W. reproduction prohibited.), 10
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 10-verso
    - Bruxelles, La Bourse. [Brussel's stock exchange], 11
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 11-verso
    - Bruxelles. -La Grand Place, a gauche l"hotel de Ville, a droite la Maison du Roi, dans le fond maisons des Corporations (F. W. Reproduction interdite). [The Grand Place, left the city hall, on the right the Breadhouse, in the background guildhalls (F. W. Reproduction prohibited)., 12
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 12-verso
    - Bruxelles. L'Eglise Ste-Gedule[Church of Saint Gedule], 13
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 13-verso
    - Bruxelles.- LePalais Royal. Au commencement du XIXe siecle une Rue separait les deux ailes, cette Rue fut supprimee en 1826, et les deux ailes reliees par un corps de batiment, dans les derniers temps on decida la demolition de toute la facade pour la remplacer par celle que nous voyons aujourd'hui. (F. W. reproduction interdite). [Royal palace of Brussels] [The Royal Palace. At the beginning of the nineteenth century a street separated the two wings. The Street was suppressed in 1826, and the two wings linked by a body building, in the last time it was decided the demolition of the entire frontage to replace the one we see today. (F. W. reproduction prohibited)., 14
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 14-verso
    - Bruxelles. Le Palais du Roi. [The King's Palace], 15
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 15-verso
    - Bruxelles Place Rogier et entr e de la Rue Neuve et du Boulevard Adolphe Max [Rogier Place and entrance to Rue Neuve, a popular shopping area in Brussels, and the Adolphe Max Boulevard], 16
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 16-verso
  - Bermuda, circa 1933; 10 (Box 1599)
    - [Hand colored postcard of the Castle Harbour Hotel], 1
    - The Castle Harnour Hotel, Bermuda., 1-verso
    - Furness Bermuda Line, Q. T. E. V. "Queen of Bermuda"., 2
    - British Made. This is a Real Photograph, 2-verso
  - Hong Kong, China, undated; 11 (Box 1599)
    - [Ships in Hong Kong Harbor], 1
    - HONG KONG- The harbor. Hong Kong is served daily by Jet Clippers* flying Pan American's 'Round the World routes., 1-verso
  - London, England, circa 1922; 12 (Box 1599)
    - West Wycombe Village., 1
    - Verso: [back of postcard], 1-verso
    - The House of Parliament, London., 2
    - LONDON. THE HOUSE OF PARLIAMENT. -The building was commenced in 1841, the architect being Sir Charles Barry. The Victoria Tower, at the extreme right of the picture is 346 feet high., 2-verso
    - Peter Pan Statue, Kensington Gardens, London., 3
    - LONDON. PETER PAN STATUE. -Presented by Sir James Barrie, the creator of Peter Pan, and erected near the Serpentine., 3-verso
    - St. Paul's Cathedral, London., 4
    - LONDON. ST. PAUL'S CATHEDRAL. -Occupies the ste of a former Gothic church. The first stone was laid in 1675, and the architect was Sir Christopher Wren., 4-verso
    - The Cenotaph, White Hall, London., 5
    - LONDON. THE CENOTAPH. -Erected to the memory of "The Glorious Dead," and unveiled by King George on November 11th. 1920., 5-verso
    - The Chames Embarkment, London., 6
    - LONDON. THE THAMES EMBARKMENT. -London's most maginificent public promenade. -The view shows thhe Hotel Cecil and Savoy Hotel, whilst in the foreground is Cleopratra's Needle., 6-verso
    - London Bridge, London., 7
    - LONDON. LONDON BRIDGE. -The present bridge was commenced in 1824. The first London Bridge is said to have been built in 994., 7-verso
    - Bukingham Palace, London., 8
    - LONDON. BUCKINGHAM PALACE. -The residence of His Majesty. The Palace is at the western end of the Mall., 8-verso
    - The British Museum, London., 9
    - LONDON. THE BRITISH MUSEUM. -The National Treasure House contains valuable collection of Books, Manuscripts, and Sculpture., 9-verso
    - The Queen Victoria Memorial, London., 10
    - LONDON. THE QUEEN VICTORIA MEMORIAL. -The Memorial was unveiled on May 16th, 1911, by King George V. in the presence of Queen Mary. The Memorial was designed and executed by Sir Thomas Brock, R.A. Upwaard of 2,000 tons of marble of the finest quality have been incorporated in the work, while some 800 tons of the finest Aberdeen granite were needed for the steps and pavement., 10-verso
    - Westminster Abbey, London., 11
    - LONDON. WESTMINSTER ABBEY. -The earliest beginings of this beautiful Abbey are lost in legend, but Edward the Confessor's building was completed A.D. 1065, Henry III commenced the present building A.D. 1245., 11-verso
    - The Mansion House, London., 12
    - LONDON. THE MANSION HOUSE. -The official residence of the Lord Mayor of London. The present building was erected in 1739., 12-verso
    - The Strand, London., 13
    - LONDON. THE STRAND. -Probably the moost famous of London's busy thoroughfares., 13-verso
    - Trafalgar Square, London., 14
    - LONDON. TRAFALGAR SQUARE. -The National Gallery is in Trafalgar Square. The Nelson Monument is on the right of the picture., 14-verso
    - The Horse Guards, Whitehall, London., 15
    - LONDON. THE HORSE GUARDS. -Upon either side of the gateway sits a mounted sentry. They are probably the most stared-at-men in London., 15-verso
    - The Grave of the Unknown Warrior, Westminster Abbey, London., 16
    - LONDON. THE UNKNOWN WARRIOR was buried on Nov. 11th, 1920, the Anniversary of Armistice Day., 16-verso
    - The Roman Catholic Cathedral, London., 17
    - LONDON. THE ROMAN CATHOLIC CATHEDRAL. -The foundation-stone of this magnificent building was laid in 1895, and the Cathedral was opened in 1903. It is situated near Victoria Stret, Westminister., 17-verso
    - The Royal Exchange and Bank of England, London., 18
    - LONDON. THE ROYAL EXCHANGE AND BANK OF ENGLAND. -The Royal Exchange ws erected in 1844, and is the third Exchange on the present site. The first was destroyed by the Great Fire, and was succeeded by another, which in turn was burnt down in 1838. The foundation-stone of the Bank of England was laid in 1732., 18-verso
    - Aldwych, London., 19
    - LONDON. ALDWYCH. -This handsome new thouroughfare connects the Strand with High Holborn. Its construction necessitated the demolition of part of the historic Seven Dials., 19-verso
    - Regent Street, London., 20